<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abel Ketema</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Abel Ketema</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 18:13:50 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How to create variable.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-5-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 18:13:50 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-5-post/</guid>
      <description>To create variable.&#xA;export DB_USERNAME=dbuser export DB_PASSWORD=secretpwdvalue export DB_NAME=mydb printenv | grep DB echo $DB_NAME &amp;#34;IF YOU WANT TO SEE&amp;#34; export DB_NAME=NEW-DB-NAME &amp;#34;To change new name&amp;#34; if you want to do it permanently you have to use &amp;#34;Vim&amp;#34; vim .bashrc &amp;#34;at the bottem&amp;#34; export DB_USERNAME=dbuser export DB_PASSWORD=secretpwdvalue export DB_NAME=mydb esc :qw source .bashrc printenv | grep DB &amp;#34;if you want to do it for all users&amp;#34; vim /etc/environment Path </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Second post how to use them</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-4-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 18:08:04 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-4-post/</guid>
      <description>diff: To find the differences between two files, use diff followed by the file names. For example, diff file1.txt file2.txt will display the lines that differ between &amp;ldquo;file1.txt&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;file2.txt&amp;rdquo;. cmp: Use cmp followed by the two file names to check if two files are identical. If there is no output, it means the files are the same. For example, cmp file1.txt file2.txt. comm: comm compares two sorted files line by line and displays lines that are common or unique between the files.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to use them?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-3-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 18:03:01 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-3-post/</guid>
      <description>How to use them?&#xA;ls: To list directories and files in the current directory, simply type ls and press Enter. You can also specify a directory as an argument to list its contents. pwd: Typing pwd and pressing Enter will display the current working directory. cd: To navigate through directories, use cd followed by the directory path you want to move to. For example, cd /path/to/directory will change the current directory to the specified path.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>IAAS, PAAS and SAAS.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-7-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 18:03:01 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-7-post/</guid>
      <description>Some inventions have been made for humanity to evolve and make life easy and fast. These day-to-day inventions support and grow a better society to the next level, especially when it comes to technology. IAAS, PAAS, and SAAS have the highest position in the technology world regarding infrastructure, platforms, and software. Different countries have to adapt to this technology or evolve to be one of the most powerful countries in the world, so it looks like the world is racing to master this technology.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Infrastructure and Host Threats.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-6-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2024 18:03:01 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-6-post/</guid>
      <description>As time passes, cloud computing continues to adapt and Sheikh towards company needs that are unique, innovative, and complex. In the IT infrastructure, businesses and developers can take many developmental approaches to provide high-quality applications and services within cloud computing. components to modern computing include scalability, applications that acquire cost effectiveness, services that include implementing invested amount of storage for these businesses, whether they are small businesses or big corporations, and allowing their applications and services to be flexible to enhance customer freedoms within their services; customers implementing their policies and procedures will allow more customer appeal to these services.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Linux code.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/name-of-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 17:09:08 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/name-of-post/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Linux sort: Sorts the lines of a file. export: Sets environment variables. zip: Compresses files into a zip archive. unzip: Extracts files from a zip archive. ssh: Connects to a remote server using the Secure Shell protocol. service: Controls system services (start, stop, restart). ps: Displays active processes. kill and killall: Terminates active processes by process ID or name. df: Displays information about disk space usage. mount: Mounts file systems.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Linux Ubuntu</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2024 12:48:18 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Linux Top 20 Linux code. Deep learning in Linux scale. I&amp;rsquo;m creating a list.&#xA;cd: Changes the current directory. mkdir: Creates a new directory. mv: Moves or renames files and directories. cp: Copies files and directories. rm: Removes (deletes) files and directories. touch: Creates an empty file or updates the access timestamp of an existing file. ln: Creates a symbolic link (shortcut) to a file or directory. cat: Displays the contents of a file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-8-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blogs/my-8-post/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
